Speaker: I’m twenty-six, so that means I’m Gen Z,
that is, the generation who were born between the nineteen nineties
and the two thousand and tens.
I haven’t read a book from the beginning to the end for years.
I get three quarters of the way through, and then I look at the last page.
I don’t want to wait to find out how the story ends – I want to know now.
It’s not just books.
I fast-forward to the middle of a song to hear the chorus –
I don’t wait to hear the verses.
Or I click to the middle of a film and watch a few minutes to see if
I really want to spend two hours of my life watching it.
I think it’s a Generation Z thing.
My friends are just as bad as me.
We send voice notes to each other because it’s quicker than texting,
but we don’t actually listen to the whole recording.
It’s easy to understand why – it’s because of social media.
First it was photos that disappeared after three seconds on Snapchat,
then it was Instagram stories with a fifteen-second time limit.
Then, during the pandemic, it was TikTok –
the videos are only a few seconds long
and the songs they feature are often played at double speed.
My mum is always telling me to slow down, and yes,
it’s true that my friends and I live life at a faster pace compared to our parents.
But it’s nothing compared to the younger generation –
their attention span is even shorter.
Today’s teenagers really do live life at double speed.
They just watch and listen to pretty much everything on fast-forward.